Guide to the Secretary of the University of Pittsburgh, John Weber, Administrative Files, 1936-1956 UA.3.4.1A
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Secretary of the University of Pittsburgh, John Weber, Administrative Files
1936-1956
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh. Secretary
UA.3.4.1A
8.75 Linear Feet (16 boxes)
This collection contains the office files of the Secretary of the University of Pittsburgh, John Weber, from 1936-1956.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred to the University Archives in 1968.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by subject as it was in the Secretary's office. Some subjects, such as the construction projects, are subarranged. File 177 has been deleted.
Previous Citation
Secretary of the University of Pittsburgh, John Weber, Administrative Files, 1936-1956, UA.3.4.1A 1936-1956, University Archives, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Scope and Content Notes
John Weber was Secretary of the University of Pittsburgh from 1936-1956. These are the adminstrative files from his office arranged per the subject index provided by his office.
Correspondence; Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Records and correspondence; Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- History; Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Administration; University of Pittsburgh; Education; University of Pittsburgh; University of Pittsburgh. Secretary; Weber, John; Stephen Collins Foster Memorial (University of Pittsburgh); Heinz Memorial Chapel (University of Pittsburgh); University of Pittsburgh -- Buildings -- Design and construction; Cathedral of Learning (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
- Alcohol Reports, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Content Notes
  During the Prohibition Era alcohol for medical, scientific and industrial purposes was strictly regulated but much needed by various laboratories, physicians and idustries. In order to allow the sale of alcohol an institution was required carefully track its dispensation. These reports document the quantities and departments that used alcohol during 1931-1932.
- Allegheny Observatory (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Correspondence about maintenance of director's residence.
- Buildings and Grounds (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Proposals mostly for Cathedral; maintenance, repair registers
- Bureaus of Sanitation, Parks, Traffic (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Campus Maps (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Cathedral of Learning Planning and Construction
  - Blueprints and Floor Plans, Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 6-10)
  - Board of Trustees Resolutions, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Building schedules, preliminary; Spandrels (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Forbes Street Terrace Construction, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Elevators (Box 2, Folder 14-19)
    Correspondence; bids; specifications, size comparisons, estimated elevator car mileage and loads; 1924-1943
  - Finishing details on Cabinetwork (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Floors, Terrazzo (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Heating and Ventilation Specifications (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Part 22, Steam Appurtenances and Piping, Steam Heating and Ventilation Apparatus
  - Observation Room (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Babcock Room.
  - Organ for Commons Room (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Partitions (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Photographs of the Construction (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Correspondence only, the actual photographs are in the UA photograph files and in UA Record Group 43.
  - Piping (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Plans and Drawings (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Plot plans. Ground plans; location on lot; cubic volume of library; chemistry, physics, dormitory buildings; blue prints; plot plans.
  - Plumbing (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Plumbing (Box 5, Folder 30-32)
  - Power Plant (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Professor's Offices (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Progress of Building, 1926-1930 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Publicity (Box 5, Folder 36-37)
  - Roofing (Box 5, Folder 38-40)
    INcludes "Specifications for the Cathedral... Part 28, Roofing, Skylights, Vents, Etc."
  - Service Entrance, Forbes Avenue (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Sewer Main, Specification (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Sewer and Plumbing (Box 5, Folder 43)
    Correspondence; blueprints; specifications; bids.
  - Skeleton specifications (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Skylights (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Space Allocation (Box 5, Folder 46)
    Present needs and estimated future needs; tentative assignments for departments; schools; space available in Cathedral of Learning within projected design, 1926.
  - Special Rooms (Box 5, Folder 47-48)
    Size and approximate cost of various projected rooms – music room, theater, library, etc. Layout of German room, 1928. Interior plans for Italian classroom. Blueprint of recreation rooms. See also FF 64.
  - Specifications, Index to (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Stairs (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Stone (Box 7, Folder 51-55)
    Correspondence, January 1930-June 1934; Correspondence January 1929-December 1929; Correspondence January 1928-December 1928; Granite facing. 10/16/1926. (blueprint removed); Masonry work. 12/15/1926
  - Structural Steel (Box 8, Folder 56-58)
    Correspondence; invoices (donations of Carnegie Steel); blueprints; clipping of "topping out" of steel structure; information about corrosion; blueprints of fireproofing; "Practical Design of Wind Bracing" by Clyde T. Morris; specifications for structural steel work; steel prices as used in other office buildings; loads; correspondence concerning foundations; soil; transmittal of blueprints and drawings; modifications; memoranda of meetings, 1924-1927; steel estimate (1925); donation of 3, 000 tons of steel.
  - Terraces (Box 8, Folder 59)
    Instructions to bidders; correspondence; proposals; orders; reports; costs; drawings. See also FF 9, 13.
  - Tests, Reports, Bids (Box 8, Folder 60-61)
    Tests of cement, steel, compression tests, inspection reports, shipment reports.
  - Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 62-65)
    Plans and specifications; observation extension; professors' offices; Yellin gates; Darlington Library; Commons Room; Heinz Chapel; Nationality rooms. See also FF 47.
  - Design and Equipment Details (Box 9, Folder 66-67)
    Design and location of water lines; sewage; telephone; Field survey, 1925.
  - Report on the Proposed Building (Box 10, Folder 68)
    Norris Report (in answer to a letter from H.L. Norris, Columbia University); Fitzgerald's letter to A.W. Mellon about proposed building 4/21/1926.
  - Subscriptions (Box 10, Folder 69-71)
    Cathedral of Learning building fund. Pledge cards. Subscription of materials, correspondence, 1925-1935; Subscriptions to building fund, Individuals; Additional subscriptions and payments.
  - Switchboard Control (Box 10, Folder 72)
    Correspondence; work schedules; materials; orders; specifications.
- City Planning Commission (Box 10, Folder 73-74)
- Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 75)
  Inquiries; student requests; complaints
- Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 76)
  Erving, Carrie; Fisher, Nairne; Gentry, Frank G.; Goldsbury, Paul E.; Greenfield, Robert A.; Griffiths, David J.; Heinz, H.J.; Herlinger, H.V.; Horner, Alena; Hospital Specialties Co.; Hunt, Percival; Hurst-Anthony Insurance Co.; Holmes, A.G.; General Electric Co. in re meter register and Watthour meter; Schisano, Charles F.; McNulty Brothers-insurance; McSorley, John.
- Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 77)
  Mahoney, Regis C.; Marks, Harry – request for employment; Corbett, Frank J.; Smith, W.L.; rental agreement for a derrick, 1934; Ohmes, Gilbert Richard; Ohmes, Arthur K.; in re Choir Festival 1932; Peoples Natural Gas; Pittsburgh Railways Company; Donatelli, Antonio; report of Scalebuoys.
- Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 78)
  In re employment of Beam, C.H.; with universities – Chicago, Florida, Miami (equipment for chemistry labs, data on Miami freshmen), list of minimum equipment requirements for teaching biology – charts, slides, supplies, etc.
- Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 79)
  University of Toronto (Hart House); Montana; Westminster College.
- Courses (Box 11, Folder 80)
  Spaced needs for classes in the College, Engineering & Mines, Business Administration, Education for 1922-1923.
- Dentistry, School of (Box 11, Folder 81)
- Duquesne Light Co. (Box 11, Folder 82)
  Contracts for service.
- Employees (Box 11, Folder 83)
  Contributions to Welfare Fund, Community Fund, 1932-1935; Allegheny County Emergency Workmen; Injury report; work records.
- Equitable Gas Co., 1930-1933 (Box 11, Folder 84)
- Evening School (Box 11, Folder 85)
- Faculty Club (Box 11, Folder 86)
  Contract and specifications for demolition of the old Faculty Club, 1931; specifications for faculty club lounge, carpet, kitchen and dining equipment; blueprint of equipment. Faculty housing correspondence; Women's Association.
- Falk Clinic (Box 11, Folder 87)
  Bid for furnishings.
- Falk School (Box 11, Folder 88)
  General Bid Specifications.
- Floors (Box 11, Folder 89)
  Care and maintenance for State, Thaw, Medical and Alumni Halls
- Foster Memorial Hall Constrtuction
  - Accounts (Box 12, Folder 90)
  - Arches and Vaults (Box 12, Folder 91)
  - Auditorium (Box 12, Folder 92)
  - Bids (Box 12, Folder 93)
  - Blueprints and Shop Drawings Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 94)
  - Board Room (Box 12, Folder 95)
  - Brick Work and Tile (Box 12, Folder 96)
  - Building codes, City of Pittsburgh (Box 12, Folder 97)
  - Cabinet Work (Box 12, Folder 98)
  - Ceiling (Box 12, Folder 99)
  - Concrete (Box 12, Folder 100)
  - Cornerstone (Box 12, Folder 101)
  - Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 102-103)
  - Dimensions (Box 12, Folder 104)
  - Doors and Windows (Box 12, Folder 105)
  - Electrical Work (Box 12, Folder 106-107)
  - Excavation and foundations (Box 13, Folder 108)
  - Hardware (Box 13, Folder 109)
  - Insurance (Box 13, Folder 110)
  - Interior details and furnishings (Box 13, Folder 111)
  - Location and floor plans (Box 13, Folder 112)
  - Modeling and carving (Box 13, Folder 113)
  - Models (Box 13, Folder 114)
  - Plumbing and heating (Box 13, Folder 115)
  - Roof and waterproofing (Box 13, Folder 116)
  - Shop drawings (Box 13, Folder 117)
  - Shrine (Museum) (Box 14, Folder 118)
  - Specifications (Box 14, Folder 119)
  - Stage (Box 14, Folder 120)
  - Steel (Box 14, Folder 121)
  - Stone (Box 14, Folder 122-123)
  - Tests (Box 14, Folder 124)
  - Daily Progress Reports, March 1935-July 1935 (Box 15, Folder 125)
  - Daily Progress Reports, August 1935-December 1935 (Box 15, Folder 126)
- Grades (Box 15, Folder 127-128)
- Heating Plant (Box 15, Folder 129-133)
  Automatic temperature control. tests, graphs; Bellefield steam distributing system, correspondence, June 1934-June 1936; Construction, specifications: Edgar Station masonry work 5/1/1928; Walpole Ring Substation, 10/20/1926; Daily reports on heating systems, October 4, 1935-June 1, 1936.
- Heating Plant (Box 16, Folder 134-137)
  Daily reports, continued; Degree day yearly data sheets, data; graphs, 1924-1934
  Burners, Articles concerning gas and oil burners: "Design and performance of domestic oil burners", Journal of the American Society of Heating and Ventilating Engineers: American Gas Association Monthly, June 1929; Natural Gas, July 1929; correspondence; coal consumption data, April-May 1929; memo on heat supply for university buildings, November 1928; heating system, costs, etc. for Carnegie Institute of Technology.
  Temperature charts; automatic temperature control; graphs; thermostat settings at various buildings; Steam consumption by building, 1933-1935; Chemistry laboratories: temperature charts and graphs, May 1936.
- Heinz Chapel Construction
  - Bids (Box 16, Folder 138)
  - Daily progress Reports, August 10, 1933-December 30, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 139)
  - Daily progress Reports, January 2, 1934-May 31, 1934 (Box 16, Folder 140)
  - Daily Progress Reports, June 1, 1934 – December 31, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 141)
  - Daily Progress Reports, January 1, 1935-May 31, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 142)
  - Daily Progress Reports, June 1, 1935-December 31, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 143)
  - Fleche (Box 17, Folder 144)
  - Specifications (Box 17, Folder 145)
- Higher Education, Division of Research In, 1928-1929 (Box 17, Folder 146)
  Course notes, no. 201 and 202.
- Hospitals (Box 17, Folder 147)
  Presbyterian University Hospital, Plumbing specifications; Eye and Ear Hospital, Plumbing specifications, 1932
- Insurance (Box 17, Folder 148)
- Library Furniture, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 149)
  Correspondence: Mr. Klimcheck with Mr. Gustav Kettere, Mr. H.J. Syran (Remington-Rand, Inc.), etc.
- Linhart, Samuel Black (Box 18, Folder 150)
  Correspondence concerning employment of Conboy and Zizmor; Use of a university-owned house (1928); Sidewalk improvements in cemetery area, 1927; Drainage on Terrace Street, 1926; Steps near Dental Building; School of Education and Teachers' Bureau office supplies budget.
- Medical School (School of Medicine) Building (Box 18, Folder 151)
  Heating, Facilities and Specifications.
- Medical Center Development (Box 18, Folder 152)
- Mellon Institute (Box 18, Folder 228)
- National Recovery Administration (Box 18, Folder 153)
  National Association of Building Owners and Managers – Codes; Printing Industry Code; President's Re-employment Program, July 27, 1933; Agreement Restaurant Industry; University employment code; hours and working conditions for employees including elevator operators, Falk Clinic personnel; custodians, watchmen, 1933. Newspaper clippings
- Office equipment and furniture (Box 18, Folder 154)
  Includes brochures on office furnishings
- Office Machines (Box 18, Folder 155)
  Installation of Hollerith Calculating Machines (IBM)
- Paint, 1928-1936 (Box 18, Folder 156)
  some specifications for paint, Cathedral and other
- Painting, 1927-1936 (Box 18, Folder 157)
  Bids and Schedules
- Parking, 1927-1934 (Box 18, Folder 158)
- Pennsylvania Hall (Box 18, Folder 159)
- Pennsylvania State University Building Plans, 1930 (Box 18, Folder 160)
- Permits and Passes (Box 18, Folder 161-162)
  For room use; fire inspection, etc; Authorization for Charles Hepner to take samples of plants growing on campus, 1932; Visiting hours, tours, permissions for visiting the Cathedral of Learning.
- Personal and other Correspondence (Box 19, Folder 163-164)
  Office hours; memos of Cathedral of Learning construction; insurance; ODK events; invitations; bills; miscellaneous; Organizations; his property; bills; son's compositions; university cafeteria profit and loss, 1928; ODK program 1929; ODK catalog and handbook, 1927; Torch Clubs – charter members list; Good Teaching, V.3 no. 9, V.3 no. 11; Klauder Christmas card; gas, water, alcohol, coal consumption charts for several buildings; personal post cards; tax receipts; "Franconia" cruise reports.
- Pharmacy,School of (Box 19, Folder 165)
- Pittsburgh Record, 1928-1929 (Box 19, Folder 166)
- Photo Naturalist (Box 19, Folder 167)
  Equipment and correspondence about the production of films about Natural History; sale of said to Eastman Kodak.
- Physical Education (Box 19, Folder 168)
  Requirements; remodeling of some facilities; summary of reports of the department including numbers of students enrolled, teacher loads, recommendations, etc., 1922-1926; improvements to Trees Gym and Field; plans for tennis courts; water and gas consumption; official rules for diving, 1929
- Physics Department (Box 19, Folder 169)
  Seismograph location (see also FF 158); costs; location of Physics in new Cathedral of Learning; equipment; floor space; pamphlet – New physics laboratories of Columbia University; Cathedral of Learning first floor plan.
- Plumbing and Plumbing Inspection (Box 19, Folder 170-171)
- Power Plant (Box 20, Folder 172)
  Data relative to conversion of Carnegie Institute power plant into a central heating station; A study to determine the advisability of discontinuing the use of the Thaw Hall power plant 1923; Specifications for lighting…1926; pamphlet of boiler tests of 1927; correspondence concerning heating fuel; concerning pumps.
- Printing (Box 20, Folder 173)
  Correspondence concerning compliance with Graphic Arts Code (National Recovery Administration); back wages due; printing orders; equipment; profit and loss statement 1929; balance sheet 1928-1929; letter concerning printing of Mammals of Pennsylvania by Samuel H. Williams; letters concerning print of bulletins, 1927; Graphic Arts Code; Bulletin about "Life at the University of Pittsburgh" 1928
- Professional Graduates (Box 20, Folder 174)
  Numbers of Pharmacy graduates 1886-1923; chart of number of physicians supplied by University of Pittsburgh; chart of relation of instruction costs, salaries, etc., 1920-1923; correspondence concerning dentists in proportion to population, 1923; professional graduates practicing in Pittsburgh; memo concerning supply of college-trained workers; growth trends; survival percentages for entering students; numbers of physicians in Pennsylvania counties; population of Western Pennsylvania counties; dentists in Western Pennsylvania; engineering alumni in Western Pennsylvania; medical school graduates 1887-1923; teachers in Western Pennsylvania counties; attorneys in Pennsylvania counties; chart of Cleveland's occupational needs; teacher certification booklet, 1924
- Proposals and Bids (Box 20, Folder 175)
  For equipment, building materials and work, etc., for Alumni Hall; Falk Clinic; fences; stadium; Medical School; State Hall; Falk School; Trees Gym, etc.
- Psychiatric Hospital (Box 20, Folder 176)
- Registrar (Box 20, Folder 178-179)
  Room assignments; registration schedules; bell times; course changes, January 1930; registration statistics 1930; scheduling of military science; admissions September 1929; grade registers; pre-registration statistics 1927-1929; University handbooks contents; distribution of credits, first semester, 1927-28; comparison of registration 1926 and 1927; statistics, 1925-35
- Rental Property, Commonwealth Realty (Box 20, Folder 180)
  Correspondence concerning rental property owned by the University; Correspondence with A.J. Kelly, Jr., of Commonwealth Real Estate Company concerning Cathedral of Learning, Stadium Road, various other properties
- Repairs (Box 21, Folder 181)
  Correspondence concerning repair work, deposits for chemistry lockers, ROTC uniforms, complaints; buildings & grds work, 1926; room changes; remodeling; fire hazards. Also a reference to heating the drawing room in Frick Acres; resolution was to do nothing since the building was in the proposed Cathedral space.
- Reports (Box 21, Folder 182)
  Engineering education. Printed reports by Committee on Admissions and Eliminations. June 1925; National Industrial Conference Board, 1923; Address by A.A. Potter, June 1925.
- Requisitions, equipment and services, 1928-1932 (Box 21, Folder 183)
- Research Bureau of Retail Training (Box 21, Folder 184)
  Correspondence; space and equipment requests; insurance plans.
- Research in Higher Education (Box 21, Folder 185)
  Offprints – "Study of Unit Costs at the University of Pittsburgh;" surveys; unit cost studies; questionnaires; faculty purchasing plan 1929; Fiscal Study of Freshman Failures 1928-29.
- Schedules (Box 21, Folder 186)
  Calendar 1934-35; mail schedule 1933; summer commencement 1922.
- Study of Scholastic Records, 1926 (Box 21, Folder 187)
  Report of an analysis of the high school class rating of incoming freshmen and their sucess into the sophmore year plus a response by A.G. Worthing (Physics)
- Seismograph Station (Box 21, Folder 188)
  Correspondence 1933-36; blueprint of seismometer pier in the Cathedral; requisitions; reports; clippings. (see also FF 169)
- Service tunnel, Cathedral of Learning (Box 21, Folder 189)
  Specifications and blueprints
- Sidewalks (Box 21, Folder 190)
  Requisitions, bids and correspondence
- Smoke control (Box 21, Folder 191)
  Violation notices 1929-33; correspondence; data on draft at Thaw Hall.
- Songbook (Box 21, Folder 192)
  Correspondence with Alumni Association about Pittsburgh Songbook.
- Space Requirements, 1922-1923 (Box 22, Folder 193)
  Special study of growth and building requirements, 1922-23; Charts; statistics; estimates
- State Hall (Box 22, Folder 196)
  Specifications for alterations to heating equipment
- Stone and Webster Engineering Corporation, 1926-1934 (Box 22, Folder 197)
  Correspondence regarding Cathedral construction
- Swimming Pool (Box 22, Folder 198)
  Trees Gymnasium Pool, correspondence; permit; reports of tests of water; water rent; handbook of ammonia-chlorine process
- Telegram Services (Box 23, Folder 199)
  Western Union rates and services for the University
- Telegraph Ledgers (Box 23, Folder 200-201)
- Thaw Hall Addition, 1929 (Box 23, Folder 202)
  Summary; blueprint; estimated costs; list of contributors to building fund
- Thermometers and Thermostats (Box 23, Folder 203)
- Time Systems (Box 23, Folder 204)
  Clocks and bells in Cathedral; electric scoreboard; athletic field clocks; blueprints of control cabinet for athletic events timer.
- Tools, 1934 (Box 23, Folder 205)
  Damage and replacement lists
- Trees Gymnasium, 1927-1932 (Box 23, Folder 206)
  Repairs to roof, floor, brickwork, caulking; Correspondence; wiring diagram
- Truck Scale (Box 23, Folder 207)
  Correspondence, 1928; blueprint, foundation and assembly plans for truck scale.
- Tuition and Fees, Association of University and College Business Officers, Eastern States, 1926-1927 (Box 23, Folder 208)
- Unit cost study, 1926-1927 (Box 23, Folder 209)
  Divisions of Research in Higher Education, Reports
- University Council, 1928-1930 (Box 23, Folder 210)
  Minutes 1928-30; elimination of the minimum age for freshmen
- University Editor, 1926-1932 (Box 23, Folder 211)
  About catalogs and bulletins
- United States History Notes (Box 23, Folder 212)
  Perhaps lecture notes.
- Unite States Steel Corporation (Box 24, Folder 213)
  U.S. Steel Corp. Correspondence re subscription toward construction of Cathedral of Learning, 1925; Report summary – "Work of the University of Pittsburgh affecting the steel industry…"; contributions of the Medical School; report on extramural classes; "Summary of data showing relation of the University to U.S. "Researches of Mellon Institute of benefit to U.S. Steel;" population of Western Pennsylvania towns and numbers of students; "Memorandum of additional service…" – includes lists of students at Pitt from various U.S. Steel towns; teachers, physicians, dentists, pharmacists, USS office workers taking evening courses, former students employed by U.S. Steel. Some information relating to Westinghouse
- Vacuum Cleaning System (Box 24, Folder 214)
  Vacuum cleaners; vacuum pump; vermin extermination; wage scale for laborers, 1932.
- Walls (Box 24, Folder 215)
  Wall construction; Correspondence; blueprint of detail of wall between turrets on Cathedral of Learning
- Wash Rooms (Box 24, Folder 216)
  Cathedral of Learning, Alumni Hall; equipment and repairs; specifications; tabulations of facilities in Cathedral of Learning; blueprints
- Water Systems and Supply (Box 24, Folder 217)
  Water rent for Trees Gym 1925-26; meters; water lines; chart of reservoirs and pumping stations
- Waterproofing (Box 24, Folder 218)
  Correspondence concerning treatment of ground cover for stadium; waterproofing of basement; waterproofing concrete, columns, sandstone, steel columns, sewers. Memoranda of conferences
- Welfare Employment, 1932-1933 (Box 24, Folder 219)
- Windows and Window Shades (Box 24, Folder 220)
- X-Ray Equipment (Box 24, Folder 221-222)
  Blueprints for apparatus; specifications; quotations; sales information; Falk Clinic
- YMCA and YWCA (Box 25, Folder 223-224)
  Correspondence; floor plan; blueprint for YMCA hut
- YMHA and YWHA (Box 25, Folder 225)
- Zoning (Box 25, Folder 226)
  Maps; ordinances; plot plans showing building heights; blueprints